Thank you. My mirror-neuron subsystem suggests that this is going to replace phones in not too long. Ray, how's it going? Ray: Great. We're live today. (Applause) MG: Ray, give the crowd a gift of the holographic brain we saw from the video earlier. Guys, this is not only going to change phones, it's also going to change the way we collaborate. Thank you so much. Thanks, Ray. Ray: You're welcome. (Applause) MG: So folks, this is the message that I discovered in that bar in 2011: The future of computers is not locked inside one of these screens. It's right here, inside of us. (Applause) So if there's one idea that I could leave you with here today, it's that the natural machine is not some figment of the future, it's right here in 2016. Which is why all hundred of us at Meta, including the administrative staff, the executives, the designers, the engineers -- before TED2017, we're all going to be throwing away our external monitors and replacing them with a truly and profoundly more natural machine. Thank you very much. (Applause) Thank you, appreciate it. Thanks, guys. Chris Anderson: So help me out on one thing, because there've been a few augmented reality demos shown over the last year or so out there. And there's sometimes a debate among technologists about, are we really seeing the real thing on-screen? There's this issue of field of view, that somehow the technology is showing a broader view than you would actually see wearing the glasses. Were we seeing the real deal there? MG: Absolutely the real deal. Not only that, we took extra measures to shoot it with a GoPro through the actual lens in the various videos that you've seen here. We want to try to simulate the experience for the world that we're actually seeing through the glasses, and not cut any corners. CA: Thank you so much for showing us that. MG: Thanks so much, I appreciate that.
Gracias. Mi subsistema de neuronas espejo sugiere que esto va a reemplazar a los teléfonos muy pronto. Ray, ¿cómo te va? Ray: Bien. Estamos en directo hoy. (Aplausos) MG: Ray, ¿no le haces un regalo al público? ¿El cerebro holográfico que vimos en el video anterior? Chicos, esta tecnología no solo cambiará a los teléfonos sino también nuestra forma de colaborar. Muchas gracias. Gracias, Ray. Ray: De nada. (Aplausos) MG: Así que amigos, este es el mensaje que descubrí en aquel bar en 2011: El futuro de la informática no está encerrado detrás de estas pantallas. sino aquí, dentro de nosotros. (Aplausos) Así que si hay una idea que quiero difundir hoy aquí, es que la máquina natural no es una ficción del futuro, está aquí en 2016. Es por eso que cientos de nosotros en Meta, incluyendo el personal administrativo, los ejecutivos, los diseñadores, los ingenieros, antes de TED 2017, tiraremos los monitores externos y los reemplazaremos por máquinas mucho más reales y naturales. Muchas gracias. (Aplausos) Muchas gracias, de verdad. Gracias, chicos. Chris Anderson: Aclárame una cosa, ya que ha habido unas cuantas demostraciones de realidad virtual en el último año, más o menos por ahí. Y a veces hay un debate entre tecnólogos sobre si realmente vemos cosas reales en la pantalla... Está el tema del campo de visión, ya que la tecnología muestra una vista mejorada de lo que en realidad se vería usando las gafas. ¿Vimos el modelo real antes? MG: Por supuesto. No solo eso, tomamos medidas adicionales para filmar con una GoPro a través de la lente real en los diversos videos que acaban de ver. Queríamos tratar de simular la experiencia del mundo que estamos viendo realmente a través de estas gafas y sin cortar nada. CA: Muchas gracias por la demostración. MG: Muchas gracias, muy agradecido.